[
  {
    "question": "These are acts or attempted acts such as to jeopardize the safety of civil aviation and air transport.",
    "options": [
      "a. Sabotage",
      "b. Act of Unlawful Interference",
      "c. Dangerous Goods",
      "d. Security"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Act of Unlawful Interference"
  },
  {
    "question": "A designated area on an apron intended to be used for parking an aircraft.",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport",
      "b. Airside waiting area",
      "c. Aircraft stand",
      "d. Apron"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Aircraft stand"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft shall be deemed to be ________ from the beginning of the pre– flight preparation of the aircraft by the ground staff or by the crew for a specific flight until twenty– four hours after any landing and the period of such service shall include the entire period during which the aircraft is in flight.",
    "options": [
      "a. In Service",
      "b. In flight",
      "c. Under Security checks",
      "d. Under Maintenance"
    ],
    "answer": "a. In Service"
  },
  {
    "question": "Space between the departures concourse and airside exists from the passenger building.",
    "options": [
      "a. Landside",
      "b. Apron",
      "c. Cargo complex",
      "d. Airside waiting area"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Airside waiting area"
  },
  {
    "question": "The non-commercial operation or use of aircraft by a company for the carriage of passengers or goods as an aid to the conduct of company business, flown by a professional pilot employed to fly the aircraft.",
    "options": [
      "a. General Aviation",
      "b. Corporate Aviation",
      "c. Civil Aviation",
      "d. Aviation Security"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Corporate Aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A device, or combination of devices and / or procedures, which are intended to detect amounts and types of explosives in passengers checked and hand carried baggage.",
    "options": [
      "a. Explosive Device Detection System",
      "b. Explosive Detection System",
      "c. DFMD",
      "d. HHMD"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Explosive Detection System"
  },
  {
    "question": "All civil aviation operations other than scheduled air services and non-scheduled air transport operations for remuneration or hire.",
    "options": [
      "a. General Aviation",
      "b. Civil Aviation",
      "c. Corporate Aviation",
      "d. Private Aviation"
    ],
    "answer": "a. General Aviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Human capabilities and limitations which have an impact on the safety, security and efficiency of aeronautical operations.",
    "options": [
      "a. Profiling",
      "b. Screening",
      "c. Human factor principle",
      "d. Human performance"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Human performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "A person who is or will be refused admission to a State by its authorities.",
    "options": [
      "a. Interline passenger",
      "b. Transit passenger",
      "c. Inadmissible passenger",
      "d. SkyMarshal"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Inadmissible passenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "A consignment of multi-packages which has been originated by more than one person, each of whom has made an agreement for carriage by air with another person other than a scheduled air carrier.",
    "options": [
      "a. Consolidated cargo",
      "b. Courier",
      "c. Dangerous Goods",
      "d. Mail"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Consolidated cargo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Measures adopted to safeguard civil aviation against acts of unlawful interference.",
    "options": [
      "a. Screening",
      "b. Profiling",
      "c. Security Audit",
      "d. Security Programme"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Security Programme"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft shall be deemed to be ________ at any time from the moment when all its external doors are closed following embarkation until the moment when any such door is opened for disembarkation.",
    "options": [
      "a. In Service",
      "b. In Flight",
      "c. Under Surveillance",
      "d. Under Maintenance"
    ],
    "answer": "b. In Flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Land side is that area of an airport and buildings to which both travelling passengers and the non-travelling public have _____________ access.",
    "options": [
      "a. unrestricted",
      "b. controlled",
      "c. restricted",
      "d. regulated"
    ],
    "answer": "a. unrestricted"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passengers are boarding an aircraft. Suddenly one passenger enters the cockpit and threatens the pilot with a knife. This incident is an example of",
    "options": [
      "a. Sabotage of aircraft",
      "b. Unlawful seizure of aircraft on ground",
      "c. Unlawful seizure of aircraft in air",
      "d. Terrorist attack on aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Unlawful seizure of aircraft on ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "Profiling is the systematic _________ of persons and baggage and questioning if necessary to categories them two group i.e. threatening and non threatening.",
    "options": [
      "a. frisking",
      "b. observation",
      "c. screening",
      "d. briefing"
    ],
    "answer": "b. observation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sterile area is the area between any passenger inspection or screening control point and the _________ into which access is strictly controlled.",
    "options": [
      "a. Boarding gate",
      "b. Aerobridge",
      "c. Ramp",
      "d. Aircraft"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aviation security is a combination of measures, human and __________ , intended to safeguard civil aviation against acts of unlawful interference.",
    "options": [
      "a. SOP’s",
      "b. Procedures",
      "c. Material resources",
      "d. SARP’s"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Material resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regulated Agent is an agent, freight forwarder or any other entity who conducts business with an operator and provides _____________that are accepted or required by the appropriate authority in respect of cargo, courier and express parcels or mail.",
    "options": [
      "a. Services",
      "b. Security control",
      "c. Commission",
      "d. Infrastructure"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Security control"
  },
  {
    "question": "The authority designated by a State within its administration to be responsible for the development, implementation and maintenance of the National Civil Aviation Security Program (NCASP)",
    "options": [
      "a. Appropriate authority for aviation security",
      "b. DGCA",
      "c. ASG",
      "d. AAI"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Appropriate authority for aviation security"
  },
  {
    "question": "A building through which cargo passes between air and ground transport and in which processing facilities are located or in which cargo is stored pending transfer to air or ground transport",
    "options": [
      "a. Cooling pit",
      "b. Baggage MakeupArea",
      "c. Cargo Building",
      "d. Cargo Area"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Cargo Building"
  },
  {
    "question": "All items, other than catering supplies, associated with passenger in-flight services, for example newspapers, magazines, headphones, audio and video tapes, pillows and blankets, amenity kits, etc.",
    "options": [
      "a. Dangerous goods",
      "b. Catering Stores",
      "c. Catering Supplies",
      "d. Cargo"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Catering Supplies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Set of procedures applied in handling, containment, and resolution of an emergency situation in planned and coordinated steps for responding to a major emergency situation in order to keep the problem from growing worse.",
    "options": [
      "a. Crisis Management",
      "b. Bomb Threat",
      "c. Standard and Recommended Practices",
      "d. Bomb Alert"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Crisis Management"
  },
  {
    "question": "A device worn by persons operating X-ray equipment to warn them of potential over exposure to radiation leakage from X-ray equipment.",
    "options": [
      "a. Airport Entry Permit",
      "b. Fanbeamgeometry",
      "c. Dosimeter Batch",
      "d. LeadShielding"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Dosimeter Batch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage of passengers subject to transfer from the aircraft of one operator to the aircraft of another operator in the course of the passenger’s journey.",
    "options": [
      "a. Suspicious bag",
      "b. Courier bag",
      "c. Handbag",
      "d. Interline baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "d. Interline baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "A person, organization or enterprise engaged in or offering to engage in an aircraft operation.",
    "options": [
      "a. BCAS",
      "b. Operator",
      "c. Airport",
      "d. ICAO"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A means by which the introduction of weapons, explosives or articles likely to be utilized to commit an act of unlawful interference can be prevented.",
    "options": [
      "a. Sabotage",
      "b. Security Control",
      "c. Sterile Area",
      "d. Hijacking"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Security Control"
  },
  {
    "question": "The application of technical or other means which are intended to identify and/or detect weapons, explosives or other dangerous devices which may be used to commit an act of unlawful interference.",
    "options": [
      "a. Security Control",
      "b. Screening",
      "c. Security Audit",
      "d. Standard and Recommended Practices"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Screening"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage, which arrives at an airport and is not retrieved or claimed by a passenger.",
    "options": [
      "a. Unclaimed baggage",
      "b. Unaccompanied baggage",
      "c. Transit baggage",
      "d. Transfer baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Unclaimed baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baggage, which is transported as cargo and may or may not be carried on the same aircraft with the person to whom it belongs.",
    "options": [
      "a. Unidentified baggage",
      "b. Unaccompanied baggage",
      "c. Interline baggage",
      "d. Transit baggage"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Unaccompanied baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "A standard practice is defined as any specification for physical characteristics, configuration material, performance, personnel or procedure, the uniform application of which is recognized as ____________ for the safety of civil aviation.",
    "options": [
      "a. Desirable",
      "b. Necessary",
      "c. Provisional",
      "d. Recommended"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Necessary"
  },
  {
    "question": "ICAO has its headquarters in.",
    "options": [
      "a. Montreal",
      "b. Chicago",
      "c. Geneva",
      "d. Paris"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Montreal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Provision and maintenance of security hold areas, frisking point, security stamps for ASGis the responsibility of ________",
    "options": [
      "a. BCAS",
      "b. Airport Operator",
      "c. Airlines",
      "d. ASG/APSU"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Airport Operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ____________ practice is any specification for physical characteristics, configuration, material , performance, personnel or procedure, the uniform application of which is recognized as desirable",
    "options": [
      "a. Recommended",
      "b. Standard",
      "c. Necessary",
      "d. Desirable"
    ],
    "answer": "a. Recommended"
  },
  {
    "question": "Convention for suppression of unlawful seizure of aircraft",
    "options": [
      "a. Chicago Convention",
      "b. Montreal Convention",
      "c. Hague Convention",
      "d. Tokyo Convention"
    ],
    "answer": "c. Hague Convention"
  },
  {
    "question": "Convention against suppression of unlawful acts against the safety of civil aviation",
    "options": [
      "a. Chicago Convention",
      "b. Montreal Convention",
      "c. Hague Convention",
      "d. Tokyo Convention"
    ],
    "answer": "b. Montreal Convention"
  }
  
  


]
